$+39\ 327\ 010\ 8283$ Via Piemonte, 2, Nerviano (MI), Italy samuele.musazzi@gmail.com

Samuele Musazzi

Fullstack Software Engineer

Extremely passionate about developing application and websites since the age of 13. More than 3 years of experience professionally developing front-end, especially with React.

I take great pride in building beautifully looking web pages and applications. Both as a hobbyist as well as a professional.

Always on the lookout for new challenges and learning opportunities that can push my career even further.

GitHub: https://www.github.com/Samx070201

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/samuele-musazzi/

SKILLS

Expert React v17+, ECMAScript 2020+ (JavaScript), TypeScript 4+, HTML 5, CSS3, C# 10, .NET 6

Entity Framework, Microsoft Azure Cloud Services, SQL, C, C++, Git Advanced

Intermediate Java, Docker, NoSQL, Azure DevOps (Continuous Integration/Continuous Deployment), Flutter,

Basic Python 3, Kubernetes

Italian (native), English (CEFR C1) with FCE Certificate Communication

Other **SCRUM**

PROJECTS SUMMARY

Agropolis Guest UI React, .NET, Azure Customers portal for ordering the company's products Agropolis Admin UI React, .NET, Azure Administrative panel for managing the resources

AB2VReact, .NET Azure DevOps extension for loggin time in the company's billing software

BePeople React, .NET AI powered innovative software for querying ERP & CMS systems

HelioS .NET WebForm Gucci's employees management system/ERP

RECENT WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Software Engineer

June 2021 — Present Triman GmbH Chiasso, Switzerland

For Agrola AG, I have designed and implemented from the ground up the front-end of "Agropolis", a web application split in two main solutions.

"Agropolis" is an administration panel and customer portal to order fuel, pellets and other materials.

Additionally, the software provides a back-office for orders management, products availability configuration & customers newsletter subscriptions.

Both of the front-ends were built using React, while the back-end was built with .NET, Microsoft SQL Server & Azure Cloud Services. In particular with the Azure Functions serverless technology.

The team organization was set-up using the SCRUM Agile methodology and I lead both the teams as SCRUM Master.

Designed and implemented from scratch "AB2V": an extension to integrate Microsoft Azure DevOps with Vertec (ERP/CRM software for logging hours for the employees) to provide a quick and simple way for Garaio AG and Triman GmbH employees to report hours directly in DevOps and have them synchronized in real time with Vertec.

This extension features a custom made UI to input the hours that have to be logged in Vertec, review any previous entry, plus a management panel to configure where the hours are going to be tracked, down to the single work item.

The front-end was built with React and the back-end with .NET & CosmosDB. It was then hosted on Azure.

In this particular scenario I also took care of setting up the entire architecture, writing the continuous integration and continuous delivery pipelines, the back-end APIs as well as the documentation on the project's wiki.

Common tools: Git, Docker, Azure DevOps CI/CD, Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, Microsoft Teams

Some other tasks that I took care of comprehend:

- Analyze customer requirements written as user stories.
- Maintain other projects and solutions.
- Pull request reviews and pair programming.

June 2019 — June 2021 Garbagnate Milanese, Italy

Developed and maintained solutions for external customers as a consultant.

I had the role of Lead Research & Development for the team.

Following a UI/UX designer model, I created the front-end of an innovative ERP querying software, called BePeople, powered by AI with dynamic user interface adapting to the user's habits and role in the company. The front-end was built with React and the back-end was a combination of .NET, Azure Cloud cognitive services (LUIS) for natural language processing/understanding and SQL Server as database.

Created the back-end for a big television rating company proprietary software, called Geca, that allowed for the analysis of metrics and habits of the viewers in Italy.

The back-end was made in .NET & RavenDB (NoSQL) with some parts also leveraging Microsoft SQL Server as a relational database.

There were multiple tasks that the back-end took care of like, for instance, integrating various data sources from other companies into our own DBs which then allowed for all the math calculations of the different metrics.

Maintained and developed new change requests as a consultant for Gucci's ERP system. I was a full-stack developer in this project and the main technology used was .NET.

I was also responsible of communicating directly with the customer and analyze the requirements to develop.

Some of other tasks that I have taken care of:

- Documentations and customer requests analysis.
- Discussions with the UI/UX designer in order to coordinate on the requested design for the product.
- Continuous research & development of new approaches and technologies to show the team.

Internship Back-end Developer

October 2018 — January 2019

Nerviano. Italy

STM Automazione

- Development of robotic arm done in C++ & MFC and installation done on field in a northern of Italy engineering company.
- Analysis & development of a C++/CLI WinForm application to be installed on a laser cutting machine.
- Networking and hardware maintenance.

Personal Projects

Personal Website

Currently developing my own personal website showcasing some of my work and giving a brief introduction to who am I and what I do as a software developer.

Shouldi

Social network written with the .NET Stack (back-end, API), Flutter (mobile) & React (web) for opinions sharing with tools for analytical insights, charts and future predicted performances. Mainly business oriented social network.

Web Scraping

Web scraping project with Selenium + Python to collect useful and filtered data to be fed in an AI model for price prediction.

EDUCATION

High School Diploma in Information Technology, I.T.I.S. Stanislao Cannizzaro

July 2019

CERTIFICATIONS

Certificated Microsoft Azure Developer: AZ-400 - Designing and Implementing Microsoft DevOps Solutions October 2020 FCE English language certificate CEFR B2 level with grades exceeding up to C1.

Hobbies

Other than being extremely passionate about IT, I am also huge into music: I play the piano and have been composing on and off for about 10 years now.

Audiophile and attentive cross-genre listener.

& much, much more...